<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Library>
    <book>
        <name>A brief history of time</name>
        <author>Stephen Hawking</author>
        <quantity>27</quantity>
        <intro>In the ten years since its publication in 1988, Stephen Hawking's classic work has become a landmark volume in scientific writing, with more than nine million copies in forty languages sold worldwide. That edition was on the cutting edge of what was then known about the origins and nature of the universe. But the intervening years have seen extraordinary advances in the technology of observing both the micro- and the macrocosmic worlds. These observations have confirmed many of Professor Hawking's theoretical predictions in the first edition of his book, including the recent discoveries of the Cosmic Background Explorer satellite (COBE), which probed back in time to within 300,000 years of the universe's beginning and revealed wrinkles in the fabric of space-time that he had projected. Eager to bring to his original text the new knowledge revealed by these observations, as well as his own recent research, Professor Hawking has prepared a new introduction to the book, written an entirely new chapter on wormholes and time travel, and updated the chapters throughout. </intro>
        <publisher>Bantam Books</publisher>
        <id>Sci_HoT</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Handmaid's Tale</name>
        <author>Margaret Atwood</author>
        <quantity>19</quantity>
        <intro>Offred is a Handmaid in the Republic of Gilead. She may leave the home of the Commander and his wife once a day to walk to food markets whose signs are now pictures instead of words because women are no longer allowed to read. She must lie on her back once a month and pray that the Commander makes her pregnant, because in an age of declining births, Offred and the other Handmaids are valued only if their ovaries are viable. Offred can remember the years before, when she lived and made love with her husband, Luke; when she played with and protected her daughter; when she had a job, money of her own, and access to knowledge. But all of that is gone now... </intro>
        <publisher>Anchor Books</publisher>
        <id>Fic_HmT</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Thirteen Reasons Why</name>
        <author>Jay Asher</author>
        <quantity>33</quantity>
        <intro>Clay Jensen returns home from school to find a strange package with his name on it lying on his porch. Inside he discovers several cassette tapes recorded by Hannah Baker–his classmate and crush–who committed suicide two weeks earlier. Hannah’s voice tells him that there are thirteen reasons why she decided to end her life. Clay is one of them. If he listens, he’ll find out why.

Clay spends the night crisscrossing his town with Hannah as his guide. He becomes a firsthand witness to Hannah’s pain, and as he follows Hannah’s recorded words throughout his town, what he discovers changes his life forever. </intro>
        <publisher>Razorbill </publisher>
        <id>Fic_TRW</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The 5 Love Languages: The Secret to Love that Lasts</name>
        <author>Gary Chapman</author>
        <quantity>21</quantity>
        <intro>Falling in love is easy. Staying in love—that’s the challenge! How can you keep your relationship fresh and growing amid the demands, conflicts, and just plain boredom of everyday life?

In the #1 New York Times bestseller The 5 Love Languages, you’ll discover the secret that has transformed millions of relationships worldwide. Whether your relationship is flourishing or failing, Dr. Gary Chapman’s proven approach to showing and receiving love will help you experience deeper and richer levels of intimacy with your partner—starting today.

The 5 Love Languages is as practical as it is insightful. Updated to reflect the complexities of relationships today, this new edition reveals intrinsic truths and applies relevant, actionable wisdom in ways that work.</intro>
        <publisher>Northfield Publishing</publisher>
        <id>Rom_5LL</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Algorithms to Live By: The Computer Science of Human Decisions</name>
        <author>Brian Christian</author>
        <quantity>11</quantity>
        <intro>A fascinating exploration of how insights from computer algorithms can be applied to our everyday lives, helping to solve common decision-making problems and illuminate the workings of the human mind

All our lives are constrained by limited space and time, limits that give rise to a particular set of problems. What should we do, or leave undone, in a day or a lifetime? How much messiness should we accept? What balance of new activities and familiar favorites is the most fulfilling? These may seem like uniquely human quandaries, but they are not: computers, too, face the same constraints, so computer scientists have been grappling with their version of such issues for decades. And the solutions they've found have much to teach us.

In a dazzlingly interdisciplinary work, acclaimed author Brian Christian and cognitive scientist Tom Griffiths show how the algorithms used by computers can also untangle very human questions. They explain how to have better hunches and when to leave things to chance, how to deal with overwhelming choices and how best to connect with others. From finding a spouse to finding a parking spot, from organizing one's inbox to understanding the workings of memory, Algorithms to Live By transforms the wisdom of computer science into strategies for human living.</intro>
        <publisher>Henry Holt and Co</publisher>
        <id>Sci_ACS</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Astrophysics for People in a Hurry</name>
        <author>Neil deGrasse Tyson</author>
        <quantity>31</quantity>
        <intro>What is the nature of space and time? How do we fit within the universe? How does the universe fit within us? There’s no better guide through these mind-expanding questions than acclaimed astrophysicist and best-selling author Neil deGrasse Tyson.

But today, few of us have time to contemplate the cosmos. So Tyson brings the universe down to Earth succinctly and clearly, with sparkling wit, in tasty chapters consumable anytime and anywhere in your busy day.

While you wait for your morning coffee to brew, for the bus, the train, or a plane to arrive, Astrophysics for People in a Hurry will reveal just what you need to be fluent and ready for the next cosmic headlines: from the Big Bang to black holes, from quarks to quantum mechanics, and from the search for planets to the search for life in the universe.</intro>
        <publisher>W. W. Norton and Company</publisher>
        <id>Sci_APH</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Lord of the Rings</name>
        <author>J. R. R. Tolkien</author>
        <quantity>19</quantity>
        <intro>A fantastic starter set for new Tolkien fans or readers interested in rediscovering the magic of Middle-earth, this three-volume box set features paperback editions of the complete trilogy -- The Fellowship of the Ring, The Two Towers, and The Return of the King -- each with art from the New Line Productions feature film on the cover.
        J.R.R. Tolkien's The Lord of the Rings trilogy is a genuine masterpiece. The most widely read and influential fantasy epic of all time, it is also quite simply one of the most memorable and beloved tales ever told. Originally published in 1954, The Lord of the Rings set the framework upon which all epic/quest fantasy since has been built. Through the urgings of the enigmatic wizard Gandalf, young hobbit Frodo Baggins embarks on an urgent, incredibly treacherous journey to destroy the One Ring. This ring -- created and then lost by the Dark Lord, Sauron, centuries earlier -- is a weapon of evil, one that Sauron desperately wants returned to him. With the power of the ring once again his own, the Dark Lord will unleash his wrath upon all of Middle-earth. The only way to prevent this horrible fate from becoming reality is to return the Ring to Mordor, the only place it can be destroyed. Unfortunately for our heroes, Mordor is also Sauron's lair. The Lord of the Rings trilogy is essential reading not only for fans of fantasy but for lovers of classic literature as well...</intro>
        <publisher>Houghton Mifflin Harcourt</publisher>
        <id>Adv_LoTR</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>A Tale of Two Cities</name>
        <author>Charles Dickens</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>After eighteen years as a political prisoner in the Bastille, the ageing Doctor Manette is finally released and reunited with his daughter in England. There the lives of two very different men, Charles Darnay, an exiled French aristocrat, and Sydney Carton, a disreputable but brilliant English lawyer, become enmeshed through their love for Lucie Manette. From the tranquil roads of London, they are drawn against their will to the vengeful, bloodstained streets of Paris at the height of the Reign of Terror, and they soon fall under the lethal shadow of La Guillotine.

This edition uses the text as it appeared in its serial publication in 1859 to convey the full scope of Dickens's vision, and includes the original illustrations by H. K. Browne ('Phiz'). Richard Maxwell's introduction discusses the intricate interweaving of epic drama with personal tragedy.</intro>
        <publisher>Penguin</publisher>
        <id>His_ToTC</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Hobbit</name>
        <author>J. R. R. Tolkien</author>
        <quantity>0</quantity>
        <intro>In a hole in the ground there lived a hobbit. Not a nasty, dirty, wet hole, filled with the ends of worms and an oozy smell, nor yet a dry, bare, sandy hole with nothing in it to sit down on or to eat: it was a hobbit-hole, and that means comfort.

        Written for J.R.R. Tolkien’s own children, The Hobbit met with instant critical acclaim when it was first published in 1937. Now recognized as a timeless classic, this introduction to the hobbit Bilbo Baggins, the wizard Gandalf, Gollum, and the spectacular world of Middle-earth recounts of the adventures of a reluctant hero, a powerful and dangerous ring, and the cruel dragon Smaug the Magnificent. The text in this 372-page paperback edition is based on that first published in Great Britain by Collins Modern Classics (1998), and includes a note on the text by Douglas A. Anderson (2001). Unforgettable!</intro>
        <publisher>Houghton Mifflin</publisher>
        <id>Adv_TH</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Da Vinci Code</name>
        <author>Dan Brown</author>
        <quantity>0</quantity>
        <intro>An ingenious code hidden in the works of Leonardo da Vinci. A desperate race through the cathedrals and castles of Europe. An astonishing truth concealed for centuries . . . unveiled at last.

While in Paris, Harvard symbologist Robert Langdon is awakened by a phone call in the dead of the night. The elderly curator of the Louvre has been murdered inside the museum, his body covered in baffling symbols. As Langdon and gifted French cryptologist Sophie Neveu sort through the bizarre riddles, they are stunned to discover a trail of clues hidden in the works of Leonardo da Vinci—clues visible for all to see and yet ingeniously disguised by the painter.

Even more startling, the late curator was involved in the Priory of Sion—a secret society whose members included Sir Isaac Newton, Victor Hugo, and Da Vinci—and he guarded a breathtaking historical secret. Unless Langdon and Neveu can decipher the labyrinthine puzzle—while avoiding the faceless adversary who shadows their every move—the explosive, ancient truth will be lost forever.</intro>
        <publisher>Anchor</publisher>
        <id>Mys_DVC</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Alchemist</name>
        <author>Paulo Coelho</author>
        <quantity>15</quantity>
        <intro>Paulo Coelho's enchanting novel has inspired a devoted following around the world. This story, dazzling in its powerful simplicity and inspiring wisdom, is about an Andalusian shepherd boy named Santiago who travels from his homeland in Spain to the Egyptian desert in search of a treasure buried in the Pyramids. Along the way he meets a Gypsy woman, a man who calls himself king, and an alchemist, all of whom point Santiago in the direction of his quest. No one knows what the treasure is, or if Santiago will be able to surmount the obstacles along the way. But what starts out as a journey to find worldly goods turns into a discovery of the treasure found within. Lush, evocative, and deeply humane, the story of Santiago is an eternal testament to the transforming power of our dreams and the importance of listening to our hearts.</intro>
        <publisher> HarperCollins</publisher>
        <id>Adv_TAl</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Memoirs of a Geisha</name>
        <author> Arthur Golden</author>
        <quantity>35</quantity>
        <intro>A literary sensation and runaway bestseller, this brilliant debut novel presents with seamless authenticity and exquisite lyricism the true confessions of one of Japan's most celebrated geisha.

In Memoirs of a Geisha, we enter a world where appearances are paramount; where a girl's virginity is auctioned to the highest bidder; where women are trained to beguile the most powerful men; and where love is scorned as illusion. It is a unique and triumphant work of fiction - at once romantic, erotic, suspenseful - and completely unforgettable. </intro>
        <publisher> Random House Large Print Publishing </publisher>
        <id>Fic_MoG</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Tea Rose </name>
        <author>Jennifer Donnelly</author>
        <quantity>15</quantity>
        <intro>East London, 1888 - a city apart. A place of shadow and light where thieves, whores, and dreamers mingle, where children play in the cobbled streets by day and a killer stalks at night, where bright hopes meet the darkest truths. Here, by the whispering waters of the Thames, Fiona Finnegan, a worker in a tea factory, hopes to own a shop one day, together with her lifelong love, Joe Bristow, a costermonger's son. With nothing but their faith in each other to spur them on, Fiona and Joe struggle, save, and sacrifice to achieve their dreams.

But Fiona's life is shattered when the actions of a dark and brutal man take from her nearly everything-and everyone-she holds dear. Fearing her own death, she is forced to flee London for New York. There, her indomitable spirit propels her rise from a modest West Side shop-front to the top of Manhattan's tea trade. But Fiona's old ghosts do not rest quietly, and to silence them, she must venture back to the London of her childhood, where a deadly confrontation with her past becomes the key to her future.</intro>
        <publisher> Harper Collins Ltd </publisher>
        <id>Rom_TTR</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Charlotte's Web</name>
        <author> E.B. White, Garth Williams and Rosemary Wells</author>
        <quantity>0</quantity>
        <intro>This beloved book by E. B. White, author of Stuart Little and The Trumpet of the Swan, is a classic of children's literature that is &quot;just about perfect.&quot;
        Some Pig. Humble. Radiant. These are the words in Charlotte's Web, high up in Zuckerman's barn. Charlotte's spiderweb tells of her feelings for a little pig named Wilbur, who simply wants a friend. They also express the love of a girl named Fern, who saved Wilbur's life when he was born the runt of his litter.
        E. B. White's Newbery Honor Book is a tender novel of friendship, love, life, and death that will continue to be enjoyed by generations to come. This edition contains color illustrations by Garth Williams, the acclaimed illustrator of E.B. White's Stuart Little and Laura Ingalls Wilder's Little House series, among many other books.
        Supports the Common Core State Standards </intro>
        <publisher> HarperCollinsPublishers </publisher>
        <id>Chi_CW</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>How to Read Literature Like a Professor</name>
        <author> Thomas C. Foster</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Ranging from major themes to literary models, narrative devices and form, Thomas C. Foster provides us with a broad overview of literature—a world where a road leads to a quest, a shared meal may signify a communion, and rain, whether cleansing or destructive, is never just a shower-and shows us how to make our reading experience more enriching, satisfying, and fun.</intro>
        <publisher> Harper Perennial </publisher>
        <id>Sci_HRLLP</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>A Foreign Policy of Freedom</name>
        <author> Ron Paul</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>There is one and only one voice in Congress for a foreign policy of freedom, and it belongs to Ron Paul, who has stood alone for freedom for many years. Ron is the seemingly impossible: a voice for reason and truth in a den of thieves.</intro>
        <publisher> Foundation for Rational </publisher>
        <id>Pol_FPoF</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Business Model Generation</name>
        <author>Alexander Osterwalder</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Business Model Generation is a handbook for visionaries, game changers, and challengers striving to defy outmoded business models and design tomorrow's enterprises. If your organization needs to adapt to harsh new realities, but you don't yet have a strategy that will get you out in front of your competitors, you need Business Model Generation.</intro>
        <publisher>John Wiley and Sons</publisher>
        <id>Bus_BMG</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Prisoners of Geography: Ten Maps That Explain Everything About the World</name>
        <author>Tim Marshall </author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Maps have a mysterious hold over us. Whether ancient, crumbling parchments or generated by Google, maps tell us things we want to know, not only about our current location or where we are going but about the world in general. And yet, when it comes to geo-politics, much of what we are told is generated by analysts and other experts who have neglected to refer to a map of the place in question.</intro>
        <publisher>Scribner</publisher>
        <id>Geo_PoG</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Vietnam: A History of the War</name>
        <author>Russell Freedman</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>In an enthralling book, Newbery Medalist Russell Freedman provides a succinct account of perhaps the most puzzling and contentious of America’s wars. Describing how a superpower caught up in Cold War politics became increasingly enmeshed in a conflict over 8,000 miles away, he then explains</intro>
        <publisher>Holiday House</publisher>
        <id>His_VHoW</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Wonder Woman: The Art and Making of the Film</name>
        <author>Sharon Gosling</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Patty Jenkins’ Wonder Woman sees the hero brought to the big screen for the first time in her own movie, and fully realizes the breathtaking wonder, strength, and grace of such an historic character. Wonder Woman: The Art   Making of the Film celebrates the creation of this groundbreaking movie, taking fans on a voyage of discovery through the world of Wonder Woman. Showcasing the earliest concept art, set and costume designs, sketches and storyboards, the book delves deep into the filmmaking process, from creating the stunning island of Themyscira to the war-torn trenches and towns of First World War Europe. </intro>
        <publisher>Titan Books</publisher>
        <id>Enc_WWAMF</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Pocket Medicine: The Massachusetts General Hospital Handbook of Internal Medicine</name>
        <author>Marc S Sabatine</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Quick access to key clinical information and solutions to common problems in internal medicine – as close as your pocket!  Pocket Medicine, Sixth Edition, is your go-to resource for fast answers to diagnostic questions you’ll face on rounds and exams. Prepared by residents and attending physicians at Massachusetts General Hospital, this portable, best-selling reference tackles the diagnosis and treatment of the most common disorders in cardiology, pulmonary medicine, gastroenterology, nephrology, hematology-oncology, infectious diseases, endocrinology, rheumatology, and neurology.  Bulleted lists, tables, and algorithms focus on the information you need in order to make an accurate diagnosis and develop a treatment plan.</intro>
        <publisher>LWW</publisher>
        <id>Enc_PMMGHHIM</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Tea Party Teddy</name>
        <author>Dianne Harman</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Tea Party Teddy is a political tell-all novel about Sacramento, California politics - the public corruption, infidelity, and greed.

Teddy, a newly elected Assemblyman, is elected because of his hateful anti-immigration platform. When he gets to Sacramento, he struggles with the temptations that ultimate power affords. His world slowly unravels as he succumbs to the power of his office. The ultimate irony occurs when his wife becomes romantically involved with the founder of the Republicans for Latinos.</intro>
        <publisher>Dianne Harman</publisher>
        <id>Sat_TPT</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>On the Road</name>
        <author>Jack Kerouac</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Jack Kerouac's groundbreaking novel—soon to be a major motion picture with a star-studded cast</intro>
        <publisher>Penguin Books</publisher>
        <id>Tra_OTR</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Travels with Charley: In Search of America </name>
        <author>John Steinbeck</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>When he was almost sixty years old, worried that he might have lost touch with the sights, the sounds and the essence of America's people, Steinbeck took note of his itchy feet and prepared to travel. He was accompanied by his French poodle, Charley, diplomat and watchdog, across the states of America from Maine to California. Moving through the woods and deserts, dirt tracks and highways to large cities and glorious wildernesses, Steinbeck observed - with remarkable honesty and insight, with a humorous and sometimes sceptical eye - America, and the Americans who inhabited it. What he saw was a lonely, generous nation too packed with individuals for single judgements; what he saw made him proud, angry, sympathetic and elated. His vision of how the world was changing still speaks to us prophetically through the decades.</intro>
        <publisher>Penguin Classics</publisher>
        <id>Tra_TWC</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Last Wish </name>
        <author>Andrzej Sapkowski</author>
        <quantity>10</quantity>
        <intro>Geralt is a witcher, a man whose magic powers, enhanced by long training and a mysterious elixir, have made him a brilliant fighter and a merciless assassin. Yet he is no ordinary murderer: his targets are the multifarious monsters and vile fiends that ravage the land and attack the innocent. He roams the country seeking assignments, but gradually comes to realise that while some of his quarry are unremittingly vile, vicious grotesques, others are the victims of sin, evil or simple naivety.</intro>
        <publisher>Gollancz </publisher>
        <id>Adv_TLW</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Time of Contempt (Witcher 2)  </name>
        <author>Andrzej Sapkowski</author>
        <quantity>5</quantity>
        <intro>Geralt the Witcher has fought monsters and demons across the land, but even he may not be prepared for what is happening to his world. The kings and armies are manoeuvring for position, each fearing invasion from across the river, each fearing their neighbours more. Intrigue, dissent and rebellion are on all sides.

The Elves and other non-humans are still suffering under decades of repression, and growing numbers join the commando units hidden deep in the forest, striking at will and then dissolving into the trees. The Magicians are fighting amongst themselves, some in the pay of the kings, some sympathetic to the elves.

And against this backdrop of fear and contempt Geralt and his lover Yennefer must protect Ciri, orphaned heir and sought by all sides. For the prophecy rests on her, and whether she lives or dies she has the power to save the world - or perhaps end it.</intro>
        <publisher>Gollancz </publisher>
        <id>Adv_ToCW2</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Sword of Destiny</name>
        <author>Andrzej Sapkowski</author>
        <quantity>9</quantity>
        <intro>Geralt is a witcher, a man whose magic powers, enhanced by long training and a mysterious elixir, have made him a brilliant fighter and a merciless assassin. Yet he is no ordinary murderer: his targets are the multifarious monsters and vile fiends that ravage the land and attack the innocent. He roams the country seeking assignments, but gradually comes to realise that while some of his quarry are unremittingly vile, vicious grotesques, others are the victims of sin, evil or simple naivety.

In this collection of short stories, following the adventures of the hit collection THE LAST WISH, join Geralt as he battles monsters, demons and prejudices alike . . .</intro>
        <publisher>Gollancz </publisher>
        <id>Adv_SoD</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>A Merciful Death </name>
        <author> Kendra Elliot </author>
        <quantity>2</quantity>
        <intro>FBI special agent Mercy Kilpatrick has been waiting her whole life for disaster to strike. A prepper since childhood, Mercy grew up living off the land—and off the grid—in rural Eagle’s Nest, Oregon. Until a shocking tragedy tore her family apart and forced her to leave home. Now a predator known as the cave man is targeting the survivalists in her hometown, murdering them in their homes, stealing huge numbers of weapons, and creating federal suspicion of a possible domestic terrorism event. But the crime scene details are eerily familiar to an unsolved mystery from Mercy’s past.</intro>
        <publisher>Montlake Romance </publisher>
        <id>Mys_AMD</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Shadow of the Wind</name>
        <author> Carlos Ruiz Zafón</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Barcelona, 1945: A city slowly heals in the aftermath of the Spanish Civil War, and Daniel, an antiquarian book dealer’s son who mourns the loss of his mother, finds solace in a mysterious book entitled The Shadow of the Wind, by one Julián Carax. But when he sets out to find the author’s other works, he makes a shocking discovery: someone has been systematically destroying every copy of every book Carax has written. In fact, Daniel may have the last of Carax’s books in existence. Soon Daniel’s seemingly innocent quest opens a door into one of Barcelona’s darkest secrets--an epic story of murder, madness, and doomed love.</intro>
        <publisher>Penguin Books</publisher>
        <id>Mys_SoW</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Part-time Princess: A Romantic Comedy</name>
        <author> Pamela DuMond</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Lucy's a down-on-her luck cocktail waitress desperate to find a job to keep her beloved uncle at Assisted Living. Lady Elizabeth hires Lucy to impersonate her for &quot;ten days tops&quot;, while she completes her pressing personal business in the States. The goal: keep Prince Cristoph of Fredonia's wandering eye in check until the real Elizabeth can return.</intro>
        <publisher>Pamela DuMond Books</publisher>
        <id>Com_PTP</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Follow You Home</name>
        <author>Mark Edwards</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>It was supposed to be the trip of a lifetime, a final adventure before settling down. But after a perfect start, an encounter with a young couple on a night train forces Daniel and Laura to cut their dream trip short and flee home.

Back in London, Daniel and Laura vow never to talk about what happened that night. But as they try to fit into their old lives again, they realise they are in terrible danger—and that their nightmare is just beginning…</intro>
        <publisher>Thomas   Mercer</publisher>
        <id>Hor_FYH</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Ghost Files</name>
        <author>Apryl Baker</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Cherry blossom lipstick: check Smokey eyes: check Skinny jeans: check Dead kid in the mirror: check For sixteen year old Mattie Hathaway, this is her normal everyday routine. She’s been able to see ghosts since her mother tried to murder her when she was five years old. No way does she want anyone to know she can talk to spooks. Being a foster kid is hard enough without being labeled a freak too. Normally, she just ignores the ghosts and they go away. That is until she see’s the ghost of her foster sister… Sally. Everyone thinks Sally’s just another runaway, but Mattie knows the truth—she’s dead. Murdered. Mattie feels like she has to help Sally, but she can’t do it alone. Against her better judgment, she teams up with a young policeman, Officer Dan, and together they set out to discover the real truth behind Sally’s disappearance. Only to find out she’s dealing with a much bigger problem, a serial killer, and she may be the next victim… Will Mattie be able to find out the truth before the killer finds her?</intro>
        <publisher>Limitless Publishing, LLC</publisher>
        <id>Hor_TGF</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Art Journey - Abstract Painting: A Celebration of Contemporary Art</name>
        <author> Jamie Markle</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Abstract art is a visual language--a riot of color, a profound explosion of texture and shape, a quiet collision of forms. Dynamic works of art can showcase pastel painting, showcase watercolor flowers, or even build off pen and ink drawings. Abstract artists are limited only by their imagination. And through instinct, composition and an inspired color palette, they translate emotions, ideas or experiences into immersive images you want to explore again and again.</intro>
        <publisher>North Light Books</publisher>
        <id>Art_AJAP</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Art That Changed the World</name>
        <author>DK</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Art That Changed the World tells the story of every major art style, movement by movement, giving art lovers a visual timeline showing key paintings that sparked each transition and explaining major events that shaped their evolution.
Each section features a lavish double-page image of an influential painting that defines each artistic style. Seminal works of genius are portrayed in their historical context, with attention paid to the culture of the time and the lives of their creators.</intro>
        <publisher>DK</publisher>
        <id>Art_ACW</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Diary of a Young Girl</name>
        <author>Anne Frank</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>In 1942, with Nazis occupying Holland, a thirteen-year-old Jewish girl and her family fled their home in Amsterdam and went into hiding. For the next two years, until their whereabouts were betrayed to the Gestapo, they and another family lived cloistered in the “Secret Annex” of an old office building. Cut off from the outside world, they faced hunger, boredom, the constant cruelties of living in confined quarters, and the ever-present threat of discovery and death. In her diary Anne Frank recorded vivid impressions of her experiences during this period. By turns thoughtful, moving, and amusing, her account offers a fascinating commentary on human courage and frailty and a compelling self-portrait of a sensitive and spirited young woman whose promise was tragically cut short.</intro>
        <publisher>Bantam</publisher>
        <id>Dia_TDoYG</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Thug Kitchen: The Official Cookbook: Eat Like You Give a F*ck</name>
        <author>Thug Kitchen LLC</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Thug Kitchen started their wildly popular website to inspire people to eatsome goddamn vegetables and adopt a healthier lifestyle. Beloved byGwyneth Paltrow ('This might be my favorite thing ever') and with half a million Facebook fans and counting, Thug Kitchen wants to show everyone how to take charge of their plates and cook up some real f*cking food.</intro>
        <publisher>Rodale Books</publisher>
        <id>Coo_TKOC</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Men's Health Big Book of Exercises: Four Weeks to a Leaner, Stronger, More Muscular You!</name>
        <author> Adam Campbell MS CSCS </author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>The Men’s Health Big Book of Exercises is the essential workout guide for anyone who wants a better body. As the most comprehensive collection of exercises ever created, this book is a body-shaping power tool for both beginners and long-time lifters alike. This book contains hundreds of useful tips, the latest findings in exercise science, and cutting-edge workouts from the world's top trainers.</intro>
        <publisher>Rodale Books</publisher>
        <id>Hea_TMH</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Popular Science</name>
        <author> Bonnier Corporation </author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>The 'What's New'&quot; magazine of science and technology. Covering the latest developments in cars, electronics, communications, tools, energy, aviation, science, space exploration and much more.</intro>
        <publisher>Bonnier Corporation</publisher>
        <id>Mag_PS</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Upstream: Selected Essays</name>
        <author> Mary Oliver </author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>So begins Upstream, a collection of essays in which revered poet Mary Oliver reflects on her willingness, as a young child and as an adult, to lose herself within the beauty and mysteries of both the natural world and the world of literature. Emphasizing the significance of her childhood “friend” Walt Whitman, through whose work she first understood that a poem is a temple, “a place to enter, and in which to feel,” and who encouraged her to vanish into the world of her writing, Oliver meditates on the forces that allowed her to create a life for herself out of work and love. As she writes, “I could not be a poet without the natural world. Someone else could. But not me. For me the door to the woods is the door to the temple.” </intro>
        <publisher>Penguin Press</publisher>
        <id>Poe_USE</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Universe of Us</name>
        <author> Lang Leav </author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Planets, stars, and constellations feature prominently in this beautiful, original poetry collection from Lang Leav.  Inspired by the wonders of the universe, the best-selling poetess writes about love and loss, hope and hurt, being lost and found.  Lang's poetry encompasses the breadth of emotions we all experience and evokes universal feelings with her skillfully crafted words.</intro>
        <publisher>Andrews McMeel Publishing</publisher>
        <id>Poe_TEU</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Theft by Finding: Diaries (1977-2002)</name>
        <author>David Sedaris </author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>For forty years, David Sedaris has kept a diary in which he records everything that captures his attention-overheard comments, salacious gossip, soap opera plot twists, secrets confided by total strangers. These observations are the source code for his finest work, and through them he has honed his cunning, surprising sentences.</intro>
        <publisher>Little, Brown and Company</publisher>
        <id>Bio_TFD</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Insomniac City: New York, Oliver, and Me</name>
        <author>Bill Hayes</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Bill Hayes came to New York City in 2009 with a one-way ticket and only the vaguest idea of how he would get by. But, at forty-eight years old, having spent decades in San Francisco, he craved change. Grieving over the death of his partner, he quickly discovered the profound consolations of the city's incessant rhythms, the sight of the Empire State Building against the night sky, and New Yorkers themselves, kindred souls that Hayes, a lifelong insomniac, encountered on late-night strolls with his camera.</intro>
        <publisher>Bloomsbury USA</publisher>
        <id>Bio_ICNOM</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Mastering Essential Math Skills: 20 Minutes a Day to Success</name>
        <author>Richard W. Fisher</author>
        <quantity>3</quantity>
        <intro>Perfect Math For Students Who Are Math Challenged

Includes award-winning online video tutorials. One for each lesson in the book.

Lessons are presented in a format that everyone can understand

Each Lesson flows smoothly and logically to the next

Each lesson is short, concise, and to the point

Lots of examples with step-by -step solutions</intro>
        <publisher>Math Essentials</publisher>
        <id>Mth_MEMS</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Everything You Need to Ace Math in One Big Fat Notebook</name>
        <author> Workman Publishing (Author), Altair Peterson (Author)</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Everything You Need to Ace Math . . . covers everything to get a student over any math hump: fractions, decimals, and how to multiply and divide them; ratios, proportions, and percentages; geometry; statistics and probability; expressions and equations; and the coordinate plane and functions.</intro>
        <publisher> Workman Publishing (Author), Altair Peterson (Author)</publisher>
        <id>Mth_EYNAM</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Wonder Woman Vol. 1: The Lies</name>
        <author>Greg Rucka</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Heroic. Iconic. Unstoppable. Armed with her Lasso of Truth and imbued with the power of the gods themselves, Princess Diana of Themyscira—known to the world as Wonder Woman—is one of the greatest superheroes in history.</intro>
        <publisher>DC Comics</publisher>
        <id>Cmc_WWV1</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>The Legend of Wonder Woman Vol. 1: Origins</name>
        <author>Renae De Liz</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>On the hidden island of Themyscira, the Amazons, led by Queen Hippolyta, live in a kingdom of peace, protected by the gods. But the balance is upset when Hippolyta is granted what no immortal may have: a child, given life from the clay of the island. She is the princess Diana, who alone can sense the evil that is infesting the Amazon’s home.
</intro>
        <publisher>DC Comics</publisher>
        <id>Cmc_TLWWV1</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Batman Vol. 1: I Am Gotham</name>
        <author>Tom King</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>He is Gotham City’s hero, its Dark Knight, its greatest protector. He is Batman. And he is not alone.

There are two new heroes in town—a pair of masked metahumans with the powers of Superman and a devotion to preserving all that is good about this twisted city. Calling themselves Gotham and Gotham Girl, they’ve saved Batman’s life, fought by his side and learned from his example.
 </intro>
        <publisher>DC Comics</publisher>
        <id>Cmc_Bat1</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Wolverine: Old Man Logan Vol. 3: The Last Ronin</name>
        <author>Jeff Lemire</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Logan is an Old Man on a mission! Given a second chance, he's determined to put right what went wrong in the reality he knew: the night the villains joined forces and overcame the world's heroes, changing his life forever. Logan lost his friends, his purpose, and all that was left was the Wasteland. Now he's back in the past, and perhaps the Villain Uprising can be prevented. But his bid to defy destiny is about to land him in trouble - deep trouble. Logan wakes up at the bottom of a well, and every time he tries to scale its walls, a mysterious figure from his future appears and riddles him with arrows. Can Logan escape his prison -and spare the world from a fate worse than death?</intro>
        <publisher>DC Comics</publisher>
        <id>Cmc_Wolv3</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>Oxford School Dictionary</name>
        <author> Oxford Dictionaries </author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>A major new edition of the trusted, bestselling, comprehensive Oxford School Dictionary with new curriculum support. This fantastic new edition will boost your children's vocabulary with new words and meanings from across the curriculum. A helpful new spelling, grammar and punctuation section is included to enhance language skills and bring the dictionary up to date.</intro>
        <publisher> OUP Oxford </publisher>
        <id>Dic_OSD</id>
    </book>
    <book>
        <name>A Dictionary of Biology 7/e</name>
        <author> Robert Hine</author>
        <quantity>1</quantity>
        <intro>Fully revised and updated for the seventh edition, this market-leading dictionary is the perfect guide for anyone studying biology, either at school or university.

With more than 5,500 clear and concise entries, it provides comprehensive coverage of biology, biophysics, and biochemistry. Over 250 new entries include terms such as Broca's area, comparative genomic hybridization, mirror neuron, and Pandoravirus.

</intro>
        <publisher> OUP Oxford </publisher>
        <id>Dic_DoB</id>
    </book>
</Library>